Inventory of the Benjamin Stoddert Ewell Papers 1784-1934
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Papers 1784-1934. (Folder 20-24)
  - Round (George C.), 15 June 1885., 1 item. Broadside. (Folder 21)
    Printed circular letter advertising as a summer resort, Belle-Air in Prince William County, Virginia, the old home of the Ewell family.
  - Scott (Elizabeth L.), granddaughter of Benjamin S. Ewell. (Folder 21)
    - An old historic town., 1 item. (Folder 21)
      An essay on Williamsburg by Elizabeth L. Scott.
    - Certificate appointing Bessie Scott, i.e., Elizabeth L. Scott, a member of the Auxiliary Board of World's Fair Managers of Virginia., 1 item. (Folder 21)
  - Scott (R. Ewell),grandson of Benjamin S. Ewell, 1894-1900., 58 items. (Folder 21)
    Papers in English, Spanish, and Japanese, including a Japanese pencil sketch.
  - Verse., 10 items. (Folder 21)
  - Roll of the artillery company of the 26th Regiment, 5th Brigade, 3rd Division, New York Militia, 1 September 1839., 1 item. (Folder 21)
  - Joint resolution of the Texas Legislature, 19 February 1863., 1 item. Certified copy. (Folder 21)
    Requesting the governor to procure exemption from military duty for employees of Eubanks & Co., cotton and wool carders.
  - Other papers., 14 items. (Folder 21)
  - Memorandum book of Elizabeth Stoddert Ewell, daughter of Benjamin S. Ewell, 17th and 18th centuries., 336 pages of which 19 pages were written upon. 13 1/2 by 9 inches. (Folder 22)
    containing data on the Ewell family, including several extracts of letters dating from the 17th and 18th centuries.
  - Genealogical notes on the Ewell and related families, 1867-1904., 64 items. (Folder 23)
  - Photographs of pages from the Ewell Family Bible. (Folder 23)
    Includes Ewell genealogical information.
  - Genealogical material about Julia McIlvaine Ewell, wife of Benjamin Ewell, from the Historical Society of York County, York, Pennsylvania. (Folder 23)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1889-1934., 22 items. (Folder 24)
  - Unidentified items and fragments., 6 items. (Folder 24)
  - Envelopes and covers., 55 items. (Folder 24)
  Series 3: Addition to collection
- Addition to collection, n.d., 31" x 36" (Othertype 2001.14A)
  Plat of Ewell property showing "Old line Bowden & Ewell."